(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-09-28T00:18:58.689737",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
おんねねー！
On-Nene!
ホロライブ5期生オレンジ担当
Hololive 5th generation, orange member,
みんなの心のエネルギー ドリンク！
everyone's spiritual energy drink!
桃鈴ねねでーーす！
I'm Momosuzu Nene!
さあ！今日はねねの誕生日！
Now, today is Nene's birthday!
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんな、ハッピーバースデーありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you for the happy birthday wishes, everyone! Thank you!
というわけで、今日はハッシュタグ
So today, please use the hashtag...
#桃鈴ねね生誕祭2024 でたくさんポストしてください！
#MomosuzuNeneBirthday24 to post a lot!
今日は今からですね、ねねの大好きなゲームで遊んだりとか
Starting from now, I'll play Nene's favorite games,
大好きなみんなと歌ったりとか
sing with everyone I love so much,
いろんなことをやっていきたいと思います！
and do all sorts of fun things!
というわけで、ねねとみんなの大冒険
So, Nene and everyone's great adventure...
行くぞーー！
Let's go!
ま、歩いていくかな。
Well, maybe I'll walk.
はあ、やっと着いた。マジ疲れた、歩いて来るの、本当に。
Sigh, I'm finally here. Walking was seriously exhausting.
わくわく！わくわく！入場しちゃうぞ！
Exciting! Exciting! I'm heading inside!
すっごい、おお！
Wow, look at that!
すっごい楽しみ！あーー！
I'm so excited! Oh!
これは！このゲームは！
No way! This game is...!
ラブandベリーじゃないの！これ！
It's Love and Berry! Oh my gosh!
ちょっと！
Wait!
しょうがない
I guess I have to...
セクシーダンスを踊ってって言ったじゃん！
I told you to do a sexy dance!
ちょっと！
Hey!
というわけで今日は...
And so, today...
まつりちゃんと、はあちゃまに来てもらいましたー！
Matsuri-chan and Haachama are here with us!
いぇーい！
Yay!
はあちゃま久しぶり！ / あ、久しぶり！
- It's been a while, Haachama!
- Ah, long time no see!
久しぶりだよー！
It's been so long!
二人はラブベリやったことありますか？
Have you two played Love and Berry before?
まつりはね、あります！
I have!
あの、オシャレ魔女です！
As in, I'm a Fashionable Witch!
わかってるねー！はあちゃまは？
You know your stuff! How about you, Haachama?
ない！ / ないんだと！
- Never!
- She says she hasn't!
本当に初めて！本当に初めて！
It's really my first time!
そっか！初見ですか、よろしくお願いします。
I see! A beginner, welcome!
じゃあまだオシャレ魔女じゃないんだ。 / オシャレ魔女じゃない！
- So you're not a Fashionable Witch yet.
- Not a Fashionable Witch!
今日はよろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you today!
はい！というわけで、今日ははあちゃまにもオシャレ魔女になってもらおうと思って。
Yep! So today, we want to make
Haachama a Fashionable Witch too.
さっそく遊んでいきたいと思います！
Let's get right into playing!
ラブベリっていうのは...
Love and Berry is a game where...
オシャレを自分でコーディネートして...
...you coordinate your own fashion...
ダンス、リズム、オシャレバトルみたいのをするんだよね。
...and do a dance, rhythm, fashion battle!
だからそれをやるには、まずオシャレ力を上げないといけないんです。
So, to do that, we first need to
raise our fashion power.
なので、それを研究するモードがあるので。
There's a research mode for that,
それで遊んで、そのあとにリズムゲームで遊んでいきたいと思います！
so we'll play that first, and then
do the rhythm game!
というわけで今回は、ねねの私物のカードを用意しました！
And so today, I brought my personal cards!
おおー！
Wow!
マジですごい！ガチ私物じゃん！
This is seriously incredible! They're really yours!
やばいやばい！
This is crazy!
これ、押したら始まるらしいんですよ。
Apparently, it starts when you press this.
ちょっとやっちゃいなよ！ / いいの？
- Go ahead and try it!
- Really?
あ、カードが出たよ！
Oh, a card came out!
え、カードが出てきた！
What, a card actually came out!
何が出てきたの？
What did you get?
あ、マジカルヘアカラー！これ、めっちゃレアなやつ！
Ah, Magical Hair Color!
This is a super rare one!
まじで？ / 髪色を変えられるやつ！
- Really?
- It lets you change hair color!
ここに置くか。あ、そこが置く場所なんだね。
I'll put it here. Ah, so that's where you put it.
で、まずはオシャレ研究モード。
And first, we do the fashion research mode.
研究って何するの？
What do you do in research?
この、ファッションに合わせて、基本コーディネートするんだよ。
Basically, you coordinate according to
the fashion scene.
時間内でコーディネートできるように練習するモード。
It's a mode to practice coordinating
within the time limit.
まずは、ねねがお手本でやっていくから。
First, I'll show you how it's done.
ラッキーカラーは青色です！ / お、青色だって！
- The lucky color is blue!
- Oh, blue!
青いドレス, 青いドレス！ / 舞踏会だから、ドレスね。
- Blue dress, blue dress!
- It's a ball, so a dress!
えーっと、じゃあこれにしようかな。
Hmm, let's see, maybe this one?
ロイヤルターコイズっていうドレス。
This dress is called Royal Turquoise.
これこれ、青だからね！ / すごい！かわいい！
- This one, because it's blue!
- Wow, so cute!
ロングアップヘアにして。
We'll go with a long updo hair.
これをスキャンして。
Scan this.
スキャンすることによって色を変えられるんだ。
You can change the color by scanning.
It looks pretty good.
あ、下がった。
Ah, the score went down.
下がった？どこで見てんの？あ、左で見てるんだ！
It went down? Where are you looking?
Ah, on the left!
そうそう。音でもわかる。
Yeah, you can tell by the sound too.
ベリーに着せたらさ...
If you dress Berry up...
あ、青、あがる、あがる！
Ah, blue! It's going up, going up!
おー、あがった、あがった！
Oh, it went up!
シューズは...
For shoes...
ジュエリーサンダル。
Jewelry Sandals.
おお、めっちゃあがった！
Oh, it went way up!
もうセットじゃん、これ！じゃあ、これで！
This is basically a complete set!
Okay, let's go with this!
ほぼ100%に近いね。
That's almost 100%! Safe!
はい！レッツゴー！
Yes! Let's go!
オシャレパワー333！すごい！
Fashion Power 333! Incredible!
あ、きた！ / アイドルステージといえばこの衣装、みたいなのあるよね。
- Ah, here it comes!
- For the Idol Stage, this is the classic outfit.
あ、めっちゃあがった！あがった！
Ah, it went way up! It went up!
ちょっと海っぽい感じのね。 / スパイシー横結び。
- A bit of a beachy vibe.
- Spicy Side Ponytail!
あ、あがった、あがった！
Ah, it went up, it went up!
ミラクルヘアカラー！あ, あがった！すごい！
Miracle Hair Color! Ah, it went up! Amazing!
アイドルステージ、いくよー！
Idol Stage, here we go!
初めて見る、アイドルステージ。 / おー、300超えた！
- First time seeing the Idol Stage!
- Oh, it exceeded 300!
というわけで、これで1回実際に対戦してみようか。
So, let's try a real match now!
いぇーい！
Yay!
リズムもかかってくるんだね、これ。 / そうそう、かかってくる！
- The rhythm part counts too, right?
- Yeah, it does!
わぁー！
Whoa!
これ、ねねのカード衣装？ / すげえ！
- Is this Nene's card outfit?
- Amazing!
あれ？
Huh?
あ、お揃いだ！お揃いのドレスしかないんじゃない！？
Ah, matching outfits!
Maybe there are only matching dresses?!
お揃い！
Matching!
まちでうわさの ラブとベリー ダンスとオシャレがだいすき
We are the rumored Love and Berry!
We absolutely love dancing and fashion!
いつもふたりはプリティ きょうもきめてる チリビッティ
The two are always pretty,
looking sharp in Chilibitty today!
でも だいじなことは みためじゃなくて
But the most important thing isn't looks...
てとてのかみ
Your hair and hands...
優しくなくちゃ
You've gotta be gentle
おしゃれしたって だめだめ
Dressing up is not enough, no, no
ココロに響く
Echoing in the heart...
リズムが大事
the rhythm is important.
ココロに響く
Echoing in the heart...
コトバが大事
words are important.
まちでうわさのラブとベリー
The talk of the town, Love and Berry,
今日も二人でベリーハッピー
both of us are very happy today, too!
明日は二人でお買い物
Tomorrow, the two of us will go shopping,
渋谷のワンコが待っている
the Shibuya puppy is waiting for us!
アイドルステージ！
Idol Stage!
はっ、びっくりした！おおー！
Ah, that scared me! Oh!
ええ！？
Eh?!
なんか光ったと思ったら...
I thought something flashed...
うちら、世界に入っちゃってたじゃん！ねえ！
We just got pulled into the game world! Right?!
てか、はーとちゃん完璧に踊ってた！すごかった！
By the way, Haato-chan danced perfectly! That was amazing!
初見じゃないから！やるって言うから練習してきたんだよー！
It's because it wasn't her first time! Because you said we were playing, I practiced!
大変だったよね、練習ね。頑張ったよね！
It must have been tough practicing. We did our best!
かわいい！じゃあ、ここでね、どっちが可愛いか勝負しよう！
Cute! So, here, let's battle to see who's cuter!
まあ、魔女としてね、一歩進んできた、ねねたち
Well, as fashion witches, Nene and the others have advanced a step.
そう、総当たり戦で優勝者を決めていきたいと思います！
Yes, we'll do a round-robin tournament to decide the winner!
なるほど！ガチ勝負！ガチ対決！いぇーい！やろう！
I see! A real match! A real showdown! Yay! Let's do it!
はーとちゃんとまつりちゃん、まつりいく？オッケー！
Haato-chan and Matsuri-chan, is Matsuri going first? Okay!
ぶとうかい まつり VS はあと
Dance Ball: Matsuri VS Haato
ピンクだ！急げ！ピンク、ピンク！
It's pink! Hurry! Pink, pink!
服は...これド定番！いきなり来ちゃうんじゃない？これ
For clothes... this is a classic! Aren't you going with this right away?
まつりちゃんっぽい！まつりちゃんっぽいかな？
That's so like Matsuri-chan! Is it like me?
demoね、ベリーの定番、ラブの定番なのだ。そうなんだ！
But you know, it's Berry's classic, Love's classic. I see!
お姫様ヘア
Princess hair.
お姫様ヘア？ああ、もう定番だね！定番、定番！
Princess hair? Ah, it's a classic! A classic, a classic!
これは、これは...ミラクルファンデーションで
This is, this is... using Miracle Foundation...
ミラクルファンデーション。おめかししないとね！おめかし、おめかし！
Miracle Foundation. Gotta dress up! Dress up, dress up!
よし、完了！はーとちゃんは緑、緑、緑！
Alright, done! Haato-chan is green, green, green!
緑はさ、何ボタンだ？どれ、どれ？これ、これ！
Which button is green? Which one, which one? This one, this one!
これ？難しい！ここに D って書いてある、これは関係ないのか？
This? So difficult! It says "D" here, is this unrelated?
ドレスの D だよ。そういうことか！
It means "D" for dress. Oh, I see!
靴！こっちもやってみなくていいの？ほら、このドレスも見てみて
Shoes! Don't you want to try this one? Look, check out this dress, too.
やってみる！この靴と、こっちのドレス合う気がする
I'll try it! I feel like these shoes and this dress match.
そう、色を変えられるんだよ。すごい！
Yes, you can change the color. Amazing!
じゃあ、ちょっとやってみよう。でも、もう時間がない！
Then let's try it. But we're out of time!
もう決められない！
I can't decide anymore!
これやって。きらパールドレス。これも定番じゃん、はーとちゃん
Let's do this. Sparkle Pearl Dress. This is also a classic, Haato-chan.
おひめさまヘア
Princess hair.
まだスリッパだよ、はーとちゃん！スリッパ嫌だ！
You're still in slippers, Haato-chan! I don't want slippers!
グリーンティンカーヒール
Green Tinker Heels.
でもちょっと、ファンキーな感じ。ちょっとね
But it feels a bit funky. A little bit.
これ、これ使って色変えたら？そうだ！
How about using this to change the color? That's right!
さっき出たカードね。なるほどね！
The card that came out earlier. I see!
ジュエリーサンダル
Jewelry Sandals.
ほら！きれい！色変わる！
Look! Beautiful! The color changed!
ミラクルフットカラー。黄色にしておくのがいい感じ？
Miracle Foot Color. Is keeping it yellow a good idea?
もうちょっとだったのにね。結構低いかも！
Even though it was just a bit more... It might be pretty low!
あ、もう時間決まったよ。357！すごい、すごい！
Ah, the time is up! 357! Amazing, amazing!
315！うわあ！
315! Wow!
でも、これ戦いだよ、これ。髪型お揃いじゃん
But this is a battle! Your hairstyles are matching.
やばい、これ初めて聞いた、これ。やばい、やばい！
Oh no, this is my first time hearing this song. Oh no, oh no!
タン、タン、タン
Tap, tap, tap...
まつりちゃんの真似するわ
I'll copy Matsuri-chan.
ずっとタンタンしてるだけ？
Are you just tapping the whole time?
え、ずっとタンタン？
Wait, is it always just tapping?
今の初見殺しだった！え、ちょっと！
That was a real surprise for first-timers! Wait, what?!
いいよ、いいよ！全然聞いてない！
Looking good, looking good! I didn't hear it at all!
なんで初見殺しの曲リズム決まってんの？
How did you nail the rhythm of a surprise song like that?
たたたたたた！
Tap-tap-tap-tap-tap!
おおー！
Oooh!
タン、タン、タン...
Tap, tap, tap...
結果発表！どっちだ！？
Result announcement! Who is it?!
お、まつりちゃんが923です！
Oh, Matsuri-chan got 923!
やったー！おめでとう！
Hooray! Congratulations!
めっちゃやったからね、このステージ！じゃあ、次！
I've played this stage so many times, after all! Alright, next up!
最初はまつりちゃんの番、レッツゴー！
First up is Matsuri's turn, let's go!
やってみましょう！いぇーい！
Let's do this! Yay!
かわいい！おっ、つぎつぎ！
Cute! Oh, next, next!
えーっと... 245！
Let's see... 245!
かわいい！おっ、クルー！
So cute! Oh, cool!
271！でもラッキーが丸なんだよね
271! But the Lucky rating is a circle.
大丈夫、いけるいける！
It's okay, you've got this!
やばい！この曲も知らん！
Oh no! I don't know this song either!
タン、タン、タタン、タタン...
Ta, ta, tatan, tatan...
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
やばい、曲が聞こえない！自分の声で！
Oh no, I can't hear the song! Just use your own voice!
自分の声で！曲が...
With your own voice! The song is...
逆にそれで妨害するしかないかもしれないｗ
In fact, that might be the only way to disrupt you!
またあしたね　バイバイ
See you tomorrow, bye-bye.
歌作ってるやん！
You're totally making up songs!
あ！パジャマおりました！パジャマおりました！
Ah! Pyjamas dropped! Pyjamas dropped!
ということで
So...
はい、ということで、今の勝負は、なんか割と滅茶苦茶でしたが、ねねの勝ち！
Yes, so even though that match was kind of chaotic, Nene wins!
音が何も聞こえなかった本当にｗ
Seriously, I couldn't hear any of the sound.
じゃあ、最強決めちゃう？最強決めちゃおうか！
Then, shall we decide the ultimate champion? Let's do it!
275！すごい！でもラッキー二重丸だ！
275! Amazing! But the Lucky is a double circle!
おおー！おっ、ラッキー二重丸！
Oh! Oh, a Lucky double circle!
おお、きた！最初からボーナスステージ！
Oh, here it comes! A bonus stage right from the start!
ABCD イカしんじゃない
ABCD, isn't it cool?
1 2 3 で ジャンプしよう
Let's jump on 1, 2, 3.
ABCD エブリバディ オッライト
ABCD, everybody alright.
1 2 3 で レッツゴー！
Let's go on 1, 2, 3!
こえも とどかないくらい
So far that even our voices can't reach.
むねに ささった おもい
The feelings that pierced my heart.
わすれかけた あのひのこと
That day that I had almost forgotten.
ABCD イカしんじゃない
ABCD, isn't it cool?
1 2 3 で ふみだそう
Let's step forward on 1, 2, 3.
ABCD イケてるスタァいじょーぶ
ABCD, a cool star is alright.
1 2 3 で OK！
OK on 1, 2, 3!
やったー！めちゃめちゃ接戦だった！すごーい！
Hooray! That was such a close match! Amazing!
いい勝負だったなー！
That was a really good match!
最終優勝者は、自分で言うのも何なんですが...
The ultimate champion, though it's a bit weird to say it myself...
ねねでーす！
...is Nene!
ねねがホロライブ一のオシャレ魔女でーす！
Nene is the number one Oshare Majo in Hololive!
さすが！いぇーい！
As expected! Yay!
えっ、最後にさ、ねねさ、もう一回みんなと踊りたいなって思ったんだけど...
Hey, lastly, Nene wanted to dance with everyone one more time...
じゃあ、あのさ、ちょうどラブとベリーがステージ行くときのポーズ、とってもらっていい？
Then, how about we strike the pose Love and Berry make when they head to the stage?
あ、そうだね！
Ah, that's right!
よーし！ストリートコートへ、レッツ・ゴー！
Alright! To the street court, let's go!
ABC de 大丈夫！
ABC de Daijoubu!
A B C D E いい感じじゃない
A B C D E, isn't it feeling good?
1 2 3 で ジャンプしよう
Let's jump on 1, 2, 3.
A B C D エブリバディ オッライト
A B C D, everybody alright.
1 2 3 で レッツゴー！
Let's go on 1, 2, 3!
こえも とどかないくらい
So far that even our voices can't reach.
むねに ささった おもい
The feelings that pierced my heart.
わすれかけた あのひのこと
That day that I had almost forgotten.
A B C D E いい感じじゃない
A B C D E, isn't it feeling good?
1 2 3 で ふみだそう
Let's step forward on 1, 2, 3.
A B C D いけてるスターいじょーぶ
A B C D, a cool star is alright.
1 2 3 で OK！
OK on 1, 2, 3!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good job, everyone!
疲れた人はこっちおいで
If you're tired, come over here.
じゃ、オシャレ魔女ビルに帰ろう
Well, let's go back to the Oshare Majo building.
いぇーい！ばいばーい！
Yay! Bye-bye!
わー！踊ってきたー！
Wow! We danced so much!
おー！ちょっとあんま飛ばないで、飛ばないで！
Oh! Wait, don't jump too much! Don't jump!
落ちちゃう！落ちちゃう！
We're gonna fall! We're gonna fall!
やめてー！
Stop it!
笑わせないで！落ちる！落ちる！
Don't make me laugh! We're falling! We're falling!
やめて！やめて！
Stop! Stop!
落ちちゃう！
We're gonna fall!
見て、カブトムシね、口ついてんだよ。
Look, the beetle balloon has a mouth.
え？カブトムシ？
Eh? The beetle?
たらこ唇でしょ？
They're cod roe lips, right?
可愛い！
So cute!
人間味あふれる口。食べないでね、私の頭。
It looks so human. Don't eat my head, okay?
キスしちゃう？
Should we kiss it?
キスしちゃおう！ついでに食べたくなっちゃうよね。
Let's do it! Though I kind of want to eat it instead.
あ、そう？ちょっといい？
Oh, really? Can I have a second?
何？
What is it?
この間にやっておかないといけないことがある。
There's something I need to do right now.
なになに？やっておかないといけないことって。
What is it? What do you need to do?
ちょっと、ついでに着替えを。
I need to quickly change my clothes.
そう、それそれ。
Yes, that's it.
え、ここでやる？どう？みんなが見てるから。
Wait, you're doing it here? With everyone watching?
あ、なるほどね。お二人はそっち向いてて。
Ah, I see. You two face that way.
私たちは見えてるけど。
We can still see you, though.
まあいいよ、見てもいい、見てもいい。
Well, that's fine. You can look, you can look.
見てほしいんだ。見ない、見ない。
So you want us to look. No way, we won't.
しょうがないな。
Can't be helped, then.
あ、ノーパン！ノーパンなだけだ！
Wait, she's commando! She's completely commando!
え、何何？本当だ！
Wait, what? Oh my god, she is!
やばい！プリプリ！お尻がやばい！
This is bad! It's so jiggly! Her butt is crazy!
プリプリ！やだやだ！
It's so jiggly! No, stop!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
早い！
That was fast!
早着替え、早着替え！おめでとー！
A quick change! Quick change! Congrats!
これね、ねねだけ着替えたのは、ねねは次のところで、あの、別のことしないといけないから。
Only Nene changed because I have to do something else at the next spot.
あ、なるほど。もうすぐ見えてくると思うんだけど。
Ah, I see. I think we'll see it soon.
え？
Eh?
あ、そこ、あそこ。
Over there, over there.
あそこか！おー！
Is that it? Oh!
あ、下ります。下りてる、下りてる！
Ah, descending. We're going down, we're going down!
じゃ、ねねはこの森で、
So, Nene is going to this forest...
ムシキングしないといけない。
To play Mushiking.
ムシキング！いいな！そうなの？
Mushiking! Nice! Really?
だから二人は先にステージで待ってて。
So you two go ahead and wait at the stage.
オッケー、待ってる。まだあるからね。
Okay, we'll wait. We still have time.
そうだよ、忘れないで休憩しててください。オッケー。
That's right, don't forget to take a break. Okay.
楽しんできてね！
Have fun!
じゃ、またあとでね！バイバイ！楽しんで！
See you later then! Bye-bye! Have fun!
ありがとう！バイバイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
はい、上がって、上がって。行くよー。
Alright, going up, going up. Here we go!
バイバイ。
Bye-bye.
わーーー！さあ、次は！
Whoaaa! Now, next up is...
甲虫王者ムシキング！
Mushiking: The King of Beetles!
こちらもセガさんに今回貸していただきました！
SEGA was kind enough to lend us this cabinet too!
というわけで、みんなと一緒に、もうこのリアルでね、このゲームセンターでムシキングをしてる当時の様子を再現したくて、
So, to recreate the feeling of playing Mushiking in an arcade back in the day with all of you...
今から生配信でやっていきたいと思います！というわけで、ムシキングをやっていくぞー！
I'm going to play it live now! So let's play some Mushiking!
というわけで、カードは今回も、ねねのカードを持ってきました！
And once again, I've brought Nene's actual cards!
ストーリーモードがムシキングにはあって、アニメとはまたちょっと違う内容でやってるので、一緒にルール説明もしながら、ストーリーモードでちょっと遊んでいきたいと思います！
Mushiking has a story mode with a slightly different plot from the anime, so I'll play that while explaining the rules!
ムシキングはね、ムシカードと...あ、今ちょうど出てる。ムシカードとわざカードっていうのがあって、それを組み合わせて相手のムシとじゃんけんで戦うみたいな感じで、じゃんけんに勝ったほうが勝ちというゲームです。
In Mushiking, there are Beetle Cards and Skill Cards... ah, they're on screen now. You combine them and battle your opponent's beetle using rock-paper-scissors. The winner of rock-paper-scissors wins.
一応、わざごとに相性があったりとかはするんだけど、それはね、興味が湧いた方はもっともっと調べてみてください。とっても奥が深いです。
There are compatibility match-ups depending on the skills, so if you're interested, please look into it! It's super deep.
というわけで、え、あ、おりゃ！
And now... heave-ho!
よいしょ。ゲームを選んでね。あ、最初まずさ、最初の白い箱、これが一番最初のやつ。
Alright, select a game. Ah, first, this white box here is the very first one.
やばい、音が！音が懐かしすぎる！う、やばい。
Oh my god, the sound! The sound is so nostalgic! Wow, this is crazy.
あ、生まれたばかりのムシを育てるんだ。
Ah, "Raise a newborn beetle."
あ、やばい。興奮しすぎてヨダレ出る。あ、これ超必殺技...
Oh my god, I'm so excited I'm drooling. Ah, this super special move...
待って待って、相手の超必殺技チョキだから、ねねはグー勝ちしたいんだよね。えっと、カブトムシに出てきてもらおう。さあ、ねねが召喚するムシ、おいで！
Wait, wait, the opponent's super special move is scissors, so Nene wants to win with rock. Let's have the beetle come out. Come on, Nene's summoned beetle!
よしよしよし。何に、何にしよう？
Alright, alright, alright. What should I choose?
え、打撃技、この下から通すハサミ技、投げ技...
Uh, hitting skill, this scissor skill from below, throwing skill...
さあ来い！ねねの、ねねのムシ！うわー！可愛い！
Now come! Nene's, Nene's beetle! Wow! So cute!
エレファス、やばい、生まれたてだからね、まだね、羽の色がちゃんとしてないんだ。
Elephas! Oh my god, it's newborn, so its wing color isn't fully developed yet.
ねねの、ねねの当時の最強デッキだよ、これ。すぐに戦います。がんばって。
This was Nene's strongest deck back in the day. Let's battle right away!
ちょっと、大きさ...
Wait, the size...
大きさがかわいそうすぎない？
Isn't the size difference too pitiful?
相手の超必殺技はチョキだから、ねねがグー出せば、もうこれ勝ちってわけ。
The opponent's super special move is Scissors, so if I play Rock, I win.
やった！超必殺技いくも！
Alright! Let's do the super special move!
ちょっともう、バランス感がかわいそうすぎる。ねねの勝ちですし、これ、完全に。
Seriously, the balance is just too pitiful. This is completely my victory.
ちょっとかわいそう。あははは！カッコいい！
A bit pitiful. Ahahaha! So cool!
あ、いい、いい。これ2発で行けるかも。
Ah, good, good. I might win this in two hits.
必殺技で勝ったあとは、また必殺技のチャンスだよ！
[Popo] After winning with a special move, you get another chance!
あ、こうやってね、あの、主人公のポポくんって言うんだけど、ポポくんが、じゃんけんのアシストをしてくれるの。
Ah, like this, the protagonist is named Popo-kun, and he assists you with Rock-Paper-Scissors.
優しい仕様なの。
It's such a user-friendly system.
ヒントというか、答えをくれる。
He practically gives you the answer instead of just a hint.
ちょっとデカすぎる。
This is a bit too big.
おお、行け！いえーい！
Oh, go! Yay!
やったね。羽が少し固まったよ。
[Popo] Way to go! The wings hardened a bit.
わあー！
Wow!
これ、みんなゲームの音聞こえてる？
Can everyone hear the game sound?
よし、今度も負けないよ。
[Popo] Alright, I won't lose this time either.
うん、聞こえる？この甲虫王者のゲームの音。
Yeah, can you hear it? This Mushiking game's sound.
きたきたきた。
Here it comes.
あ、見て。ちょっと羽が、ちょっと羽が茶色くなってる。
Ah, look. The wings... the wings are a bit brown.
最初は気をつけて！
[Popo] Be careful at first!
「最初は気をつけて」ってことは、これね、チョキでくるの。
Since he says "Be careful at first", they'll start with Scissors.
必殺技にするから、ねねはグーだ。
Since they'll use a special move, I'll play Rock.
やった！超必殺技！
Alright! Super special move!
「気をつけてね」のときは、相手の得意な技がくるんだよね、大体。
When it says "Be careful", the opponent will usually use their specialty move.
このストーリーモードとかだと、このポポのアシストでほぼ勝てる。
In this story mode, you can almost always win with Popo's assists.
必殺技を喰らってフラフラしている。チャンスだよ！
[Popo] They're dizzy from the special move. It's your chance!
あ、これはね、「もう1回出せる」ってことなんだと思う。
Ah, this means "you can use it one more time", I think.
はい、きた！フラフラしてるから、もう1回必殺技出したら最強だよ、みたいな。
There we go! Since they're dizzy, using a special move again is the strongest move.
アシストがくるの。
That's the assist you get.
ポポさん最強だから。
Popo-san is the strongest.
ポポさん、また？
Popo-san, again?
やった！羽がもっと固まったよ。もう少したね。
[Popo] Way to go! The wings hardened even more. Just a bit more.
おおー！こんな羽がやわやわのときに戦っちゃって。あ。
Oh! Fighting while the wings are still soft like this. Ah.
アクター？アクター？
Adder? Adder?
アダーの赤い目の虫に見つかってしまった！
[Popo] We've been spotted by Adder's red-eyed beetle!
マルスか。「アダーの赤い目」っていうのは、あの、ポポの、敵、森の中の、妖精界の敵みたいなのがいるんだけど、その人は、
Mars, huh. "Adder's red eyes" refers to Popo's enemy in the forest of the fairy world...
虫を赤い目に改造して、
...who modifies the beetles to have red eyes...
改造して、赤目にして、無理やり...
...modifying them and forcing them to...
あ、このおじさん、このおじさん。このおじさんに戦わせようとしてるの。
Ah, this old man, this old man. He's making them fight.
これを倒して、赤い目の、このアダーコレクションっていうんだけど、この赤い目の虫から解放してあげる、みたいな。
We defeat this and free them from the red-eyed state, from the "Adder Collection" as they call it.
のをするの。解放してあげる意味。
That's what we do. It's to free them.
マルスゾウカブト、さっさと片付けろ。
[Adder] Mars elephant beetle, finish it quickly.
さっさと片付けろってことは、必殺技っぽいから、ねねはパーを出そうとした。あ、違う？
Since he says "finish it quickly", it feels like a special move, so I should play Paper. Wait, no?
やばい！あ、でも、
Oh no! Ah, but,
これこれ！カキンカキン、チュリチュリチュリ。
This is it! Clash, clash, chirp chirp chirp.
はあー、この音、この音。
Haa, this sound, this sound.
ふははは、ポポ、もう後がないぞ。
[Adder] Fuhahaha, Popo, you have nowhere left to run.
え、これは必殺技いっちゃうか。
Eh, should we use a special move here?
「後がないぞ」っていうことは、「必殺技を出すしかないぞ」って今、アシストをもらってるのさ。
When he says "you have nowhere left to run", it's an assist telling me "you have to use a special move now".
アダーもなんか、やるじゃん。
Adder is quite something, too.
まあ、エレファントが最強ってわけ！
Well, the Elephant beetle is the strongest!
これ！この音！
This! This sound!
羽が固まったよ。もう今までの体に戻りました。
[Popo] The wings hardened. They're back to their normal body now.
いっぱい触っとかないと！いっぱい触っとかないと。
I have to touch them a lot! I have to touch them a lot.
うむ、完全体になりおった。ブルーマイスター、やつを血祭りにあげろ。
[Adder] Hmm, it has reached its complete form. Blue Meister, make a bloodbath of them.
あ、ブルマイ！ブルーマイスターツヤクワガタじゃん、これ！
Ah, Blue-My! This is a Blue Meister stag beetle!
きたきたきた。あ、やばい。超必殺技がMAX...
Here it comes. Ah, oh no. The super special move is maxed...
気をつけて！僕たちの手を呼んでいるよ！
[Popo] Be careful! They're calling for our move!
「僕たちの手を呼んでいる」ってことは、グーを出そうとしてるから、パーを出そう、そしたらチョキ。
"They're calling for our hand" means they're trying to play Rock, so we play Paper, then Scissors.
じゃあ、ローリングクラッチホールド！
Then, Rolling Clutch Hold!
痛そうだなって思ってたんだよね、ずっと。
I've always thought that looked really painful.
あ、でも、あんま入んない、やっぱ、さすがにちょっと強い。
Ah, but it didn't do much damage, they're really strong after all.
動きが変だ。僕たちの手を呼んでいるよ！
[Popo] Their movement is strange. They're calling for our move!
えーっと、ってことは、グー、チョキだから...
Uh, so that means Rock, Scissors...
あ、やばい、負けちゃう！
Ah, oh no, I'm going to lose!
あ、行くか？きたきたきた！
Ah, are we going? Here it comes!
めきめきめき、そうなんだよ。めきめきめきって言うんだよ。
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, yeah, that's it. It makes a crushing sound.
アダー、もうあきらめろ！
[Popo] Adder, give up already!
あ、これ、うんだな。もう諦めろの時はうんなんだけど。
Ah, this must be a "yes" move. When it says "give up already", it's a sure win.
あ、やばいやばい！やばい！あ、必殺技、はいはいはい。
Ah, oh no! Oh no! Ah, special move, I see, I see.
これね、なんか、わざカードにも2パターンあって、
You see, skill cards also have two patterns...
なんか、攻撃する技と、なんか、他のわざとか、虫のアシストみたいのをするカードもあるの。
...like attacking skills, and other cards that provide assists to the beetles.
ブルーマイスター、とどめをさすのじゃ。
[Adder] Blue Meister, deliver the finishing blow.
あ、やばいやばいやばいやばい、やられた！
Ah, oh no, oh no, oh no, I got hit!
やばい！やばい！やばい！やばい！あ、まずい！
Oh no! Oh no! Oh no! Ah, this is bad!
焦った！
I panicked!
あ、ちょっとエレファス！
Ah, wait, Elephas!
だめだよ！必殺技...あ、やばい、負けちゃった。
No way! A finishing move... Oh no, I lost.
君は負けてしまった。
"You have lost."
なんてこった。
What a disaster.
「友達と対戦して腕を磨くんだ。」
"Train your skills by battling your friends."
あ、スパコレ。これ持ってますね。
Oh, Spacolle. I have this one.
これね、虫の育成もできるし。
With this, you can also raise beetles, and...
はい、次のお友達はいないんで、ねねが連プレイです。
Yep, there's no "next friend," so Nene is playing again!
いないんで。
Since there's no one.
一人なんで。切な。
Since I'm alone. How sad.
えーっと、これね。
Um, this one.
この改造コーチュウのところのストーリーを見ると、このアザークコレクションのところ...
If you watch the story of this modified beetle part, this other collection part...
え、わかるんだよ。
...you will understand.
「ポポ、面白いものを見せてやろう。」
"Popo, I will show you something interesting."
そう、どうやってこの、あの、このアザーの虫が生まれてきているかみたいな。
Yeah, like how this other beetle is born.
ねね昔はさ、ここ、ここが可哀想すぎて、すらっと行けなかった。
In the past, Nene felt so sorry for them here that I couldn't just breeze through it.
さあ、さあ、さあ、ねねの、ねねのムシくん。
Now, now, now, Nene's... Nene's beetle!
さあ、何かな？
Now, what is it?
でも相手の必殺技パーだからね。
But the opponent's finishing move is Paper, you see.
ねねはチョキ勝ち、チョキ勝ちしていきたいところではある。
Nene wants to win with Scissors, win with Scissors.
えい！
Ei!
来たー！
It's here!
ギラファ！ギラファノコギリクワガタ！
Giraffa! Giraffa Stag Beetle!
はい、はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
よし、よし、よし、よし、相手の必殺技に注意、パー。すぐに戦う。あ、ほら、ほら見て。
Okay, okay, okay, okay, beware of opponent's finishing move Paper. Fight immediately. Ah, look, look!
後ろでさ。
In the background...
「最初は必殺技でくるよ、気をつけて！」
"They will use a finishing move first, watch out!"
最初は必殺技でくるから、パーで、チョキ。パーとチョキ。
Since they'll use their finishing move first, which is Paper, I'll use Scissors. Paper and Scissors.
いいの？
Is this okay?
ブルロック出ちゃう、いいの？
Bull Lock is coming out, is that okay?
これ読み込ませたら、このスキャナーの上に置くのが、あの2のやり方だから。
Scanning it, then putting it on top of the scanner, that's how we did it in version 2.
戻さない、ケースに。
I won't put it back in the case.
「アラー、何をしているんだ？あれは一体何なのだ？」
"Allard, what are you doing? What on earth is that?"
あ、やばい。ポポのアシストが足りない。
Oh, no. Popo's assist is missing.
「教えてやろう、最終兵器...」
"I shall tell you, the ultimate weapon..."
こうやって。
Like this...
あ、やばいやばい、生まれてくる。こうやって改造して無理やり戦わせてるの。
Ah, oh no, it's being born. They modify it like this and force it to fight.
酷すぎる。
That's too cruel!
でも、ムシキングのカードにはアザーコレクションっていうのもあって、その赤い目を。
But, there's also the Other Collection among the Mushiking cards, and those red eyes...
こっち側にして戦うこともできる。見て、あ、超かっこいい。
...we can also fight with them on our side. Look, oh, super cool!
はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
「サブに何とひどいことをやらせるんだ。」
"How can they make Sub do such a terrible thing?"
やばい、もう蛹からだいぶ変えちゃってて、痛々しい気がするけどな。
Oh no, they already changed it a lot from the pupa stage, it looks quite painful.
「フフ、無駄じゃ。もうすぐ分かる。」
"Hehe, it is useless. You will find out soon."
アルキデスオオヒラタクワガタ。
Alkides Stag Beetle.
もうビチビチなんだから、このフレームいっぱいに名前書いてある。
It's so tightly packed, its name is filling up the whole frame!
やばい、もうほぼ生まれてんだよね、見えてる見えてる。
Oh no, it's almost born, we can see it, we can see it.
「最初は気をつけて。」
"Watch out at first!"
最初は気をつけてってことは、必殺技出てくるからパー。
Since they say "watch out at first", a finishing move is coming, so Paper.
ローリングドライバーね！
Rolling Driver!
これね、みんな大好きローリングドライバー。
This one, everyone's favorite, Rolling Driver.
パー技の定番。
The classic Paper move.
「見ろ、ついに完成の時が来た。最強のパラワンオオヒラタじゃ！」
"Look, the time of completion has finally arrived. The strongest Palawan stag beetle!"
やばい！
Oh no!
「まだうまく動けないんだ。」
"It still can't move properly."
途中に。
In the middle of it...
そうだよね、でもまだうまく動けない時に、さっきねね戦わせちゃったんだよな、あいつ。
Right, but Nene made him fight earlier when he couldn't move properly.
「あいこの後だよ、ヒントを思い出して！」
"After a tie! Remember the hint!"
あいこの時は、もう一回出してこようとするから。
In a tie, they'll try to throw the same thing again, so...
グー。
...Rock.
百裂拳いきます！
Here comes Hundred Fists!
いぇーい！
Yay!
え、なんかさ。
Eh, somehow...
「今出した技に勝ちにくるよ。」
"They will try to beat the move you just played!"
グーに出し勝ちにいくから、パーとチョキ。
They'll try to beat Rock, so Paper and Scissors.
なんかねねが、ねねがこのデッキで行くわって、ブラザーに見せたら、甘いなって言われた。
When Nene showed my brother "I'm going with this deck", he said "You're naive."
ダメなんだよね、そういうパワーで押し通そうとしたら、サポートの技入れないとダメだよって言われた。
He said, "That's no good, trying to push through with raw power like that. You have to include support moves."
なんか、なんかめっちゃ悔しかったわ。
Somehow, I felt so frustrated.
「ここでは羽が固まらないようじゃな。パラワンオオヒラタ、外に出るぞ。ついて来い！」
"It seems its wings won't harden here. Palawan, we are going outside. Follow me!"
わ、何ておじさんだ。
Wow, what an old man.
「パラワンオオヒラタの羽が固まるまで、時間を稼ぐのだ！」
"Buy time until Palawan's wings harden!"
おい、リッキー！リッキーに時間稼がせようとすんなよ！
Hey, Ricky! Don't try to make Ricky buy you time!
最強これ、もうこれボーイズみんなの憧れなんだから。
This is the strongest, it's what all the boys dream of!
「怒るんだ！僕たちの手を読んでいるよ。」
"Get angry! They're reading our moves!"
チョキを出したいというのが分かっているから、向こうはグーを出してくるから、ねねはパー。
They know I want to throw Scissors, so they'll throw Rock, which means Nene will throw Paper.
うわー！最強や！
Whoa! This is the strongest!
リッキーとギラファの戦い、めっちゃ熱くない？
Isn't the fight between Ricky and Giraffa super intense?
「気をつけて！僕たちの手を読んでいるよ。」
"Watch out! They're reading our moves!"
あ、手を読んでいる、もう一回か。
Ah, they're reading our moves, so one more time?
「リッキーブルー、さっさと片付けろ！」
"Ricky Blue, clean this up quickly!"
来た、来た！
Here it comes, here it comes!
ほい、これのために、この、ひ、超必殺技合わせしてんだよ
Hey, I matched up this super special move just for this!
え、ムシキングってこう、こういうゲーム。やりたくなっちゃうよね
So, Mushiking is... this kind of game. It makes you want to play it, doesn't it?
うーん、これが楽しくて、これが楽しくて
Mmm, this is so much fun, this is so much fun...
羽が乾く前に、勝負をつけなきゃ。急ごう！
We must finish this before your wings dry. Let's hurry!
さいごのてき
The Final Enemy
ねねの行きつけだったのは
The place Nene used to frequent was...
あ、ジャスコとか
Ah, like Jusco,
トイザらス
or Toys "R" Us.
色んな、各地を回って、全然並んでないところを探す
I'd travel around to different places looking for locations with no lines at all.
最後のヘンゲだ！僕たちの手を信じているよ！
The final transformation! We believe in our hands!
あ、アイツ、チョキで、チョキに、グーで対抗するか
Ah, he's using scissors. Should I counter his scissors with rock?
あ、さらに読まれている。読みが...
Ah, I'm being read even further. The reading...
「パラワンオオヒラタ！さっさと片付けろ！」あ、片付けろ言われた
Palawan! Finish it quickly! Ah, he told him to finish it.
あ、まずい！
Ah, this is bad!
やばい、ノコギリクワガタとして、ヒラタクワガタに負けられない。わ、どうしよう
Oh no, as a saw-toothed stag beetle, I can't lose to a flat-headed stag beetle. What should I do?
あ、え、まずい、まずい、まずい、やばい、あ、もっとヒートアップ！まずい、まずい
Ah, eh, bad, bad, bad, oh no! Ah, heating up even more! Bad, bad!
「高き羽を見つめ、つねにかんせいしゃであれ！」完全になっちゃった、やばい
Gaze upon the high wings, and always be perfect! He became complete! Oh no!
あぶ！やめて！
Ah! Stop!
あっぶねー！
That was close!
「パラワンオオヒラタ、とどめをさすのじゃ」さすがに、さすがに超必殺技は...
Palawan, deliver the finishing blow. As expected, the super special move is...
「きまった」うわ、あつ、あ、まずい！
It's decided. Whoa, hot! Ah, this is bad!
あ、あ、ああー、ねねのギラファがー！
Ah, ah, aaah! Nene's Giraffe stag beetle!
何すんだよ！
What did you do?!
え、ちょっと、勝ちの時、勝ちの時の画面も見たい
Eh, wait, I want to see the victory screen too!
あ、よいしょ
Ah, there we go.
膝が、膝がもう、力入れすぎちゃって。あ、次の...
My knees, my knees... I put too much strength into them. Ah, the next...
あ、いない、いない、いない、いないわ、これ
Ah, there's no one. No one, no one. There's no one here.
これね、次のお友達がいる時は、大体もう、こうやってずっと画面を見られてるし
You know, when there are other friends waiting, they usually just stare at your screen like this,
交換できるカードがないかどうかずっと見られてるんよな
and they keep watching to see if you have any cards to trade.
はあー...
Haaa...
ええーっと、という、これもう一回やってもいいんだ、いいんでしたっけ？
Umm, so, can I play this one more time? Was that allowed?
あ、あ、うん、あ、もう出来ない、もう出来ない、時間がないって
Ah, ah, yeah... Ah, I can't anymore. I can't. They say there's no time.
あー、これ欲しい
Ah, I want this.
これ欲しいってわけで、改めてセガさん、今回は本当にありがとうございました！
I want this, so once again, SEGA, thank you so very much for this opportunity!
え、じゃあ最後にね、ま、この今広い、クソ広い森の中に、来ていますので
Well then, lastly, since we are in this wide, incredibly wide forest right now,
ねねのムシキングの愛、というか、虫への愛、ムシキングへの愛を、え、歌いたいと思います。
I would like to sing Nene's love for Mushiking, or rather, love for bugs, love for Mushiking.
というわけでね、ゲーム版ではなく、アニメ版の、あのムシキングの曲、え、聞いてください。生きてこそ！
So, not the game version, but the anime version of the Mushiking song... please listen to it. "Ikite Koso"!
ママ、私が生まれた日の
"Mama, what color was the sky
空はどんな色?
on the day I was born?"
パパ、私が生まれた日の
"Papa, how did you feel
気持ちはどうだった?
on the day I was born?"
あれから言葉を覚えて
Since then, I've learned words,
私なりの愛も甘え方も
and my own ways of loving and acting spoiled
体に染み込んだ
have soaked deep into my body.
生きてこそ
Living is what matters,
living is what matters,
今ここから始まる
starting right here, right now.
生きてこそ
Living is what matters,
living is what matters,
広がってまた繋がる
spreading out and connecting once again.
ママ、私を初めて抱く
"Mama, how did you feel
気持ちはどうだった?
when you held me for the very first time?"
パパ、私が生まれた日の
"Papa, on the day I was born,
嬉しかった?
were you happy?"
あれから奇跡を重ねて
Since then, through a series of miracles,
私なりの愛も出会いも
and my own way of loving and meeting people,
育ててゆきたい
I want to nurture them.
生きてこそ
Living is what matters...
Because we are alive...
無限に羽ばたいてく夢
Dreams that flap their wings infinitely
生きてこそ
Because we are alive...
その根は深く太く強く
Those roots go deep, thick, and strong
生きてこそ
Because we are alive...
今ここから始まる
Beginning right here, right now
生きてこそ
Because we are alive...
広がってまた繋がる
Spreading out and connecting once again
生きてこそ
Because we are alive...
無限に羽ばたいてく夢
Dreams that flap their wings infinitely
生きてこそ
Because we are alive...
その根は深く太く強く
Those roots go deep, thick, and strong
Yeah!
羽ばたいて
Flap your wings...
生きてこそ
Because we are alive...
ああ
Ah...
はい！というわけで「生きてこそ」でした！
Yes! And that was "Because We Are Alive"!
ねぇ見て！なんか木漏れ日の光たちがさ、こう舞ってく感じが
Look! The sunlight filtering through the trees, the way it's floating around...
めっちゃ表現されてるでしょ、このキラキラで！
is captured so beautifully with all this sparkle!
えー、というわけで、えー
Well then... um...
よっこいしょ！
Up we go!
はい、上がってください！
Okay, please take me up!
よいしょ！よいしょ！
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
えー、皆さん、今はえー虫キングの世界にいたんですけど
Um, everyone, just now we were in the world of Mushiking...
ま、ねねの大好きな、虫、ギラファノコギリクワガタ
Well, Nene's favorite beetle, the Giraffe Stag Beetle...
ヘラクレス、今日はちょっと出す用意はしてたんだけどね、出す機会がなかったヘラクレス
I actually had Hercules ready today, but didn't get a chance to show him. Hercules!
えー、色んな虫たちへのねねの大好きな思いを込めて作った曲が、あるよね？
There's a song filled with all of Nene's love for various beetles, right?
というわけで、それをみんなで歌いたいと思います！
So, I'd like to sing that song with everyone!
ステージがね、なんかその辺にあるんだけど
The stage is... well, it's around here somewhere...
あ！あ！あそこ！あそこ！
Ah! Ah! Over there! Over there!
ハッピーギラファ！
Happy Giraffa!
ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！
Welcome to Nenechi's Giragira Fan Meeting!
今日は、一緒に踊ってくれる人たちが来てくれてるみたいなので
Today, it looks like some friends are here to dance with me,
呼んでみたいと思います！
so I'd like to call them out!
それじゃあ、いくよ！
Alright then, here we go!
アミーゴ！カケーロ！ビバ！
Amigo! Kakero! Viva!
ギラファ！
Giraffa!
カブ！クワ！ヘイ！
Kabu! Kuwa! Hey!
ギラギラ最高だね！
Sparkling is the best, right?
カブ！クワ！
Kabu! Kuwa!
アモーレカブクワ！イェイ！
Amore Kabu-Kuwa! Yay!
カブ！クワ！ヘイ！
Kabu! Kuwa! Hey!
くりくりおめめラブ
Round eyes, I love them
カブ！クワ！
Kabu! Kuwa!
アモーレカブクワ！イェイ！
Amore Kabu-Kuwa! Yay!
愛の！
Love!
脱皮はモ～チョ！モ～チョ！
Shedding skin is almost... almost!
飛んで！
Fly!
シュビドゥバメロメロ
Shoo-be-doo-bah, madly in love!
みんな！
Everyone!
集まれゾロゾロ
Gather around in crowds!
チュッチュッ
Chu-chu-
チュッチュッチュッ
-chu-chu-chu!
パヤパヤパヤパ！
Paya paya payapa!
ギラギラギラファン！
Gira gira gira-fan!
キラキラキラファン！
Kira kira kira-fan!
ギラギラギラファン！
Gira gira gira-fan!
キラキラキラファン！
Kira kira kira-fan!
目が覚めたなら元気に「おはよう」
Once you wake up, say "Good morning" with energy!
レッツゴー！カブクワパラダイス！
Let's go! Kabu-Kuwa Paradise!
おしゃれなんてそっちのけ出かけよう
Forget about dressing up, let's go out!
いってらっしゃい！
Have a safe trip!
エレファス！
Elephas!
コーカサス！
Caucasus!
ヘラクレス！
Hercules!
ノコギリタランドゥス！
Nokogiri Tarandus!
ファンミーティングが始まるよ！
The Fan Meeting is starting!
出逢いに！
To our encounter!
アミーゴ！カケーロ！ビバ！
Amigo! Kakero! Viva!
ギラファ！
Giraffa!
カブ！クワ！ヘイ！
Kabu! Kuwa! Hey!
ギラギラ最大級！
Maximum sparkling!
カブ！クワ！
Kabu! Kuwa!
アモーレカブクワ！イェイ！
Amore Kabu-Kuwa! Yay!
カブ！クワ！ヘイ！
Kabu! Kuwa! Hey!
てかてかつやつやのカブ！
Shiny, glossy Kabu!
クワ！
Kuwa!
もちゃ もちゃ
Mocha, mocha!
かわいい！
So cute!
世界をペロペロ
Licking the world!
みんな！
Everyone!
あつまれ ゾロゾロ
Gather around, one after another!
Chu! Chu! Chu! パヤパヤ パヤパ
Chu! Chu! Chu! Paya paya paya pa!
甘酸っぱいバナナと砂糖少々
A tart banana and a little sugar...
ぷりぷりおがくず加えましょう
...and let's add some plump sawdust!
両手でクワッと 鷲掴み
With both hands, grab tight with a "kuwa"!
揉んで 揉んで 揉んで 揉んで！
Knead, knead, knead, knead!
交差したツノはジュエリ
Our crossed horns are jewelry!
マイボディ見せ合おうジュエリ
Let's show off our bodies, jewelry!
カブクワは弾けりゃ ノリたれ！
If the beetles pop, get into the groove!
サッサッ サッサッサッ サッサッ サッサッサッ
Sa-sa, sa-sa-sa! Sa-sa, sa-sa-sa!
乗ったら揺らせ
Once you get on, shake it!
ユッサッ ユッサッサッ ユッサッ ユッサッサッ
Yussa, yussa-sa! Yussa, yussa-sa!
落ちなきゃあったけえ！
As long as you don't fall, it's warm!
バンバン バンバンバン バンバン バンバンバン
Bang, bang, bang-bang-bang! Bang, bang, bang-bang-bang!
これだけゃ踊れ
Make sure to at least dance to this!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
すごーい！
Amazing!
ホロメンたちのおかげで...
Thanks to the Hololive members...
こんなにたくさんのカブト・クワガタたちが集まってくれたよ！
...so many beetles and stag beetles have gathered!
みんなに、拍手！
A round of applause for everyone!
そしてもちろん、ねねにも拍手ー！
And of course, a round of applause for Nene too!
アヌビス レギウス マルマルス 虹色グランディス
Anubis, Regius, Marmoratus, Rainbow, Grandis...
みんなそれぞれ愛してるけど やっぱり君が好き
I love each and every one, but you're still my favorite!
ギラファ ギラファ ギラファ ギラファ ギラファ ギラファ
Giraffa, Giraffa, Giraffa, Giraffa, Giraffa, Giraffa...
強くてカッコいい ギラギラ
Strong and cool, glittering!
ファンタスティックなそのアゴにメロメロ だからもう君のものだよ
I'm head over heels for those fantastic mandibles, so I'm yours!
ビバ！ ギラファ！ ビバ！ ギラファ！
Viva! Giraffa! Viva! Giraffa!
カブクワ ギラギラ最高踊れ
Kabu-Kuwa! Glittering is the best, let's dance!
カブクワ アモーレ カブクワ イェーイ
Kabu-Kuwa, Amore! Kabu-Kuwa, yay!
カブクワ クリクリお目々ラブ
Kabu-Kuwa! Love those round eyes!
カブクワ アモーレ カブクワ イェーイ
Kabu-Kuwa, Amore! Kabu-Kuwa, yay!
Chu! Chu! Chu! パヤパヤ パヤパ
Chu! Chu! Chu! Paya paya paya pa!
パヤパヤ パヤパ！
Paya paya paya pa!
ねえねえ これ怖い
Hey, this is scary...
あたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
A-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Wa-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, dokkyun!
ずきゅん！
Zukkyun!
どきゅん！
Dokkyun!
ずきゅん！
Zukkyun!
やだやだやだやだ ねばねばねば！
No, no, no, no, never, never, never!
チェケラ チョコレート チョコレート チョッチョッチョ いいかな？
Check it out, chocolate, chocolate, cho-cho-cho, is it okay?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと最近 心配なんです<
But wait a minute, lately I'm a bit worried...
だけどチョコレート チョコレート チョッチョッチョ いいかな？
But chocolate, chocolate, cho-cho-cho, is it okay?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと待って チョチョッチョ
But wait a minute, wait a sec, cho-cho-cho!
あたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
A-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Wa-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, dokkyun!
ずきゅん！
Zukkyun!
どきゅん！
Dokkyun!
ずきゅん！
Zukkyun!
まだまだまだまだ ねばねばねば！
Not yet, not yet, never, never, never!
チェケラ チョコレート チョコレート チョッチョッチョ いいよね？
Check it out, chocolate, chocolate, cho-cho-cho, it's fine, right?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと最近 心配なんです
But wait a minute, lately I'm a bit worried...
だけどチョコレート チョコレート チョッチョッチョ いいよね？
But chocolate, chocolate, cho-cho-cho, it's fine, right?
でもねちょっとウェイト ちょっと待って チョチョッチョ
But wait a minute, wait a sec, cho-cho-cho!
パラッパッパッパ パラッパッパッパ パラッパッパッパ パパパパン
Pa-ra-pa-pa-pa-pa, pa-ra-pa-pa-pa-pa...
Too late! Too late! Too late! P-P-P-Please, come on!
あたたたたーたたーたたーたたーずっきゅん！
Atatata ta-ta ta-ta ta-ta zukkyun!
わたたたたーたたーたたーたたーどっきゅん！
Watatata ta-ta ta-ta ta-ta dokkyun!
ずきゅん！ どきゅん！ ずきゅん！ どきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
やだやだやだやだ ねばねばねばねば
No way, no way, no way, no way! Sticky, sticky!
ちょっとハート ちょいいっぱい 頑張ったんです
I worked really hard, put a little bit of heart into it!
だからちょっとハート ちょっとだけ お願いなんです
So a little bit of heart, just a little bit, is my request!
早くチョコレート チョコレート ちょっちょっちょーだい
Hurry up, chocolate, chocolate, please give me some!
よこせチョコレート チョコレート Please!
Hand over the chocolate, chocolate, please!
チョコレート チョコレート ちょっちょっちょーいいでしょう
Chocolate, chocolate, a little bit is fine, right?
だよねちょっとグッと 超ハッピーで頑張っちゃうんです
Right, feeling intense, working hard in super happy mode!
だからチョコレート チョコレート ちょっちょっちょーいいでしょう
So chocolate, chocolate, a little bit is fine, right?
だよねちょっとだけ ちょっとだけ 食べちゃうの
Right, just a little bit, I'll eat just a little bit!
パパパパ パパパパ...
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa...
Too late, too late, too late, too... Pee pee pee, come on!
Too late, too late, too late, too... Pee-pee-pee, come on!
パパパパ パパパパ...
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa...
あたたたたーたたーたたーたたー
Atatata ta-ta ta-ta ta-ta...
あたたたたーたたーたたーたたー...
えー、P・K・Bのポーズしてみたいと思います！
Now, we would like to try the P.K.B pose!
はーい！まずは私たちから...。もうやったじゃん、さっき
Yay! First from us... Wait, we already did it earlier!
P！ P！ P！
P! P! P!
K！ K！ K！
K! K! K!
B！ B！ B！ がんばれB！
B! B! B! Hang in there, B!
というわけで、私たちP・K・Bでした！
And that's why we were P.K.B!
みんなギミチョコ一緒にやってくれてありがとねー！
Thank you everyone for doing Gimme Chocolate with us!
めっちゃ疲れたよ、お疲れ様ー！
I'm so tired! Good work, everyone!
というわけで、ねねはまだあるんで、がんばって！
So, Nene still has more to do. Good luck!
退場！散れ！散れ！
Exit! Disperse! Disperse!
まつりちゃん！はーちゃん！
Matsuri-chan! Ha-chan!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
はい！あの、大変盛り上がってるところ恐縮なのですが...
Yes! Well, I'm sorry to interrupt while everyone is so hyped...
ねねからのお知らせをさせてくださーい！
But please let Nene make an announcement!
お知らせはこちらです！ドン！
Here is the announcement! Bam!
お誕生日を記念したグッズが発売されまーす！イェーイ！
My birthday commemorative merchandise is going on sale! Yay!
え、もう見て丸わかりの通り、西沢5㍉先生にキービジュアルを書いてもらいました！
As you can clearly see, Nishizawa 5㍉-sensei drew the key visual for me!
今回は、まあお風呂とかお風呂上がりとかそういう感じのイメージのコンセプトで作っております！紹介していきます。まずは、こちら！
They're designed with a concept based on baths and post-bath vibes! Let's show them. First is this!
えー、西沢5㍉先生の描いてくれたイラストの、B2のタペストリーです！
A B2 tapestry featuring Nishizawa 5㍉-sensei's illustration!
なんかこう、お風呂上がりにね、ちょっと飲み物なんか飲んじゃって、あ、ぱぱって、あぱぱってしてる感じの、ねねのB2のタペストリー！
It's Nene chilling out and having a drink after a bath on a B2 tapestry!
これ絶対に、絶対に大きいので、絶対にサイズ感が大きいので、皆さんぜひ手に入れてください！
This is definitely big, the size is absolutely huge, so please make sure to get one!
そして次が、こちら！
And next up is this!
え、缶バッジです！3種入り！最近ね、あの、痛バとか作ってくれる人がX見てて多くて
Can badges! A set of three! Recently, I've seen many people making ita-bags on X,
缶バッジもっと増えたらいいなと思って缶バッジにしました！
so I thought it'd be great to have more, and made these badges!
イラストはね、いつも可愛い、あの、ファンアートを書いてくれてる山猫先生に書いていただきました！ありがとう！
The illustrations were drawn by Yamaneko-sensei, who always draws cute fan art! Thank you!
え、そして続きましてはこちら！
And moving on, next is this!
え、ビールジョッキ！まあビールジョッキって書いてあるんだけど、風呂上がりにぷはっとね、あの一杯飲み物をいただけちゃうビールジョッキが出ます！
A beer mug! It's called a beer mug, but it's a mug where you can enjoy a refreshing post-bath drink!
ねね、配信のご飯時のときが多いので、これでみんなで一緒にご飯時にぷはーしましょう！
Nene often streams during dinner, so let's all say 'puhaah' together at dinner with this!
そして、なんかお風呂っぽいの1個欲しいなと思ってこちら！
And next, I wanted something bath-related, so here's this!
サウナホルダー！
A sauna holder!
なんかあの、お風呂行ったときに、外のお風呂に行ったときに、あの鍵かけるときに使うやつ、あの鍵のやつで
It's like that key strap thing you use to hold the locker key when you go to a public bath.
女、これでお頭を縛り上がりますね、これで
For girls, you can tie up your hair with this.
これまとめ上がりまして、あの、鍵をなくさないのと同時に、髪をまとめ上がります、これで
It ties it up, so you won't lose your key while keeping your hair securely back!
え、で、それのキーホルダー！なんかちょっとお湯っぽい感じのねねが描いてあって、色はねっこの色にしてあります！
And it's a keychain version! It has a slightly bath-styled Nene, and the color is Nekko color!
そして続きましてはこちら！
And continuing on, here is this!
え、ボイス！シチュエーションボイス「ねねちのお風呂ボイス」！
Voice! Situation voice: 'Nenechi's Bath Voice'!
というわけでね、一緒に入ってるか入ってないかは、みんなの耳で...
So, whether we're bathing together or not is up to your own ears to...
確かめてください。
Please check it out.
そして今回も、えー、フルセットの購入特典があります！こちら！
And this time as well, there's a bonus for purchasing the full set! Here it is!
えー、フルセットを買っていただきますと、え、ポストカードと特典のボイスがついてきます。こちら！
If you purchase the full set, it comes with a postcard and a bonus voice! Here it is!
購入特典はね、見て、みんな。あの、お顔がね、ちょっともう酔っぱらっちゃっちゃっちゃっぴーみたいな感じの顔になってるポストカードと、
For the purchase bonus, look, everyone. A postcard with a face that looks a bit tipsy and drunk,
え、直筆サイン＆箔押しの複製メッセージ入りポストカード。
and a postcard with a handwritten signature and foil-stamped duplicated message.
そして、お風呂上がりに一杯、喉が渇いて飲んじゃって、
And also, after getting out of the bath, you get thirsty and have a drink,
「あ、酔っ払っちゃっちゃっちゃ？」みたいなボイスがついてきます。
and then getting tipsy... a voice like that is included!
ぜひ、ぜひぜひぜひ、
Please, please, please...
よろしくお願いします。ありがとうございます。
I hope you'll consider it. Thank you very much!
え、そしてですね、今回、本当はねぽらぼ全員呼びたかったんですけど、
And also, this time, I actually wanted to invite all of Nepolabo,
ま、タイミングとか、ちょっと体調のこともありまして、ラミィが来れかったんですよ。
but due to timing and health reasons, Lamy couldn't make it.
でも、「ラミィ、あと、なんか、なんか頂戴！」って言ったら、お手紙をくれたので、
But when I asked, "Lamy, give me something, anything!" she sent me a letter,
ラミィのお手紙、ねね、まだ見てないので、ここで晒していきたいと思います。
so since I haven't read it yet, I'm going to expose Lamy's letter here!
これです！
This is it!
「Happy Birthday! いつも周りの人を笑顔に、そして元気をくれるねねが大好きだよ。」
"Happy Birthday! I love Nene, who always makes everyone around her smile and gives us energy."
「ポンコツなところも、アイドルに全力！なところも、全部大好き。」
"I love everything about you, even your clumsy side, and how you give your all as an idol."
あ、これ2人で歌った「歌ってみた」の時のやつですね。
Ah, this drawing is from the cover song we sang together!
ラミィちゃん、いい子、いい絵。なんか、いいじゃないの、なんか。
Lamy is such a good girl, and it's a great drawing! Isn't it wonderful?
これはちょっと、後で現像して額に入れることにします！
I think I'll print this out later and put it in a frame!
というわけで、今日はタイミング的にラミィはいなくて、
So, Lamy couldn't make it today due to timing,
そして、おまるはね、今日、無事に戻ってきたということで、お祝いも込めて、
but Polka has safely returned today, so to celebrate her return as well,
最後は、えーっと、ねぽぽ！
for the last song, Nepopo!
3人で歌っていきたいと思います！
The three of us are going to sing!
それでは最後、レッツゴー！いでよ！
With that, here's our final song. Let's go! Come on out!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
はい！はい！
Hey! Hey!
君がいないと何もできないの
I can't do anything without you
君のごはんが食べたいよ
I want to eat your home-cooked meals
もし君が帰ってきたら とびきりの笑顔で
If you come back home, with the biggest smile...
抱きつくよ
I'll run and hug you tight
君がいないと謝れないよ
Without you here, I can't even apologize
君の声が聞きたいよ
I want to hear your voice
君の笑顔が見れれば
If only I could see your smile,
それだけでいいんだよ
that alone would be enough
君がそばにいるだけで
Just having you by my side
いつも勇気もらってた
always gave me courage
いつまででも一緒にいたい
I want to be with you forever
この気持ちを伝えたいよ
I want to tell you how I feel
晴れの日も 雨の日も
Whether it's sunny or rainy,
君はそばにいてくれた
you were always there by my side
目を閉じれば 君の笑顔
If I close my eyes, your smile...
輝いてる
is shining bright
君がいないと何もわからないよ
Without you here, I don't know anything
砂糖と醤油はどこだっけ？
Where are the sugar and soy sauce kept?
もし君が帰ってきたら びっくりさせようとも結構
Even if I think of surprising you when you return,
思ってたのにな
I realized that was just a passing thought
君についつい甘えちゃうよ
I always find myself depending on you
君が優しすぎるから
Because you are just way too kind
君にもらってばかりで
I'm always on the receiving end,
何もあげられてないよ
and I haven't been able to give you anything back
君がそばにいることを
Having you by my side...
当たり前に思ってた固定
I had started to take it for granted
こんな日々がずっとずっと
I thought these days would go on
続くんだと思ってたよ
forever and ever
ごめん、今は気づ...
I'm sorry, now I rea...
気づいたよ
...I realized
あたりまえじゃないことに
that it's not something to be taken for granted.
まずはキミに伝えなくちゃ
First, I must tell you...
ありがとう
...thank you.
ありがとう！届いてるかー？！
Thank you! Is it reaching you?!
聞こえてますかー？！
Can you hear us?!
超元気でやってます！
We're performing with super energy!
キミの胸に届くかな
Will it reach your heart?
今は自信ないけれど
I don't have much confidence right now, but...
笑わないで どうか聞いて
Please don't laugh, just listen.
想いを歌に込めたから
Because I put my feelings into this song.
ありったけの ありがとう
With all the gratitude I can give,
歌に乗せて 届けたい
I want to deliver it on this song.
この気持ちは ずっとずっと
These feelings, forever and ever,
忘れないよ
I will never forget them.
想いよ 届け
May my feelings reach you!
ジャン、ジャン、ジャン、ジャン！
Strum, strum, strum, strum!
もう一回！
One more time!
ジャン、ジャン、ジャン、ジャン！
Strum, strum, strum, strum!
やばい！やばい！やばい！やばい！桃鈴ねね生誕2024 遊んでみた
[Text: Yabai! Yabai! Yabai! Yabai! Momosuzu Nene Birthday 2024 - Played Around]